Guide to the Beecher Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Correspondence, 1806-1818, 1822-1849, (1850-1930), 1931-1948, 1964; Series I; 19' (46 boxes)
  - Beecher-Scoville Family Correspondence
    - Scoville, Harriet Eliza (Beecher)
      - To H. E. S.:
        - Stoughton, Elizabeth C., 1908 (Box 39, Folder 1737)
        - Stowe, Charles Edward (1850-1934), 1897 (Box 39, Folder 1738)
        - Stowe, Harriet Beecher (1836-1907), 1987-1998, undated (Box 39, Folder 1739)
        - Strong, Augustus H., 1902 (Box 39, Folder 1740)
        - U.S. Department of State, 1859 (Box 39, Folder 1741)
        - Upton, Lucy H.M., 1902 (Box 39, Folder 1742)
        - Vail, Mamie Sanford, undated (Box 39, Folder 1743)
        - Van Clift, Katherine Bellows, 1908 (Box 39, Folder 1744)
        - Van Idenstine, Addie, 1908 (Box 39, Folder 1745)
        - Vintner, T. H., 1902 (Box 39, Folder 1746)
        - Walworth, Lillian E., 1909 (Box 39, Folder 1747)
        - Wheeler, Harriet M., 1902 (Box 39, Folder 1748)
        - Wheeler, Mrs. Hayden W., 1908 (Box 39, Folder 1749)
        - Unidentified Relatives (Box 39, Folder 1750)
        - Unidentified (Box 39, Folder 1751)
      - From H.E.S.:
        - Beach, Chloe Buckingham, 1868-1888, undated (Box 39, Folder 1752)
        - Beecher Family. (Box 39, Folder 1753)
          See: Box 1, Folder 48 Box 1, Folder 55 Box 2, Folder 87
        - Howard, Annie (d. 1860) (Box 39, Folder 1754)
        - Howard, John Raymond (1837-1926), 1860 (Box 39, Folder 1755)
        - Edward, Susan Taylor (Raymond), 1860 (Box 39, Folder 1756)
        - Jewert, C.C., 1872 (Box 39, Folder 1757)
        - To her Children, 1881-1902, undated (Box 39, Folder 1758)
        - Her family, 1859-1860 (Box 39, Folder 1759)
        - Scoville, Katherine (Trumbull), undated (Box 39, Folder 1760)
    - Scoville, Rev. Samuel
      - To Rev. S.S.:
        - Abbott, Benjamin Vaughn (1830-1890), undated (Box 40, Folder 1762)
        - Associated Charities, 1900 (Box 40, Folder 1763)
        - Allen-Arthur, 1891-1907 (Box 40, Folder 1764)
        - Bates, Katharine Lee (1859-1929), undated (Box 40, Folder 1765)
        - Beach, Moses Sperry (1822-1892), 1884 (Box 40, Folder 1766)
        - Beard, Rev. Augustus F., 1856-1879, undated (Box 40, Folder 1767-1769)
        - Beecher, Catharine Esther, 1860 (Box 40, Folder 1770)
        - Beecher, Charles, 1896-1899 (Box 40, Folder 1771)
        - Beecher, Eunice White (Bullard), 1869-1883, undated, 1863-1885, 1886 July-1889, 1891-1896, undated (Box 40, Folder 1772-1777)
        - Beecher, Henry Barton, 1887-1898 (Box 40, Folder 1778)
        - Beecher, Henry Ward. (Box 40, Folder 1779)
          See: Box 14, Folders 573-576
        - Beecher, Thomas Kinnicut, 1864-1888 (Box 40, Folder 1780)
        - Beecher, William Constantine, 1873-1884 (Box 40, Folder 1781)
        - Bliss, Rev. Howard Sweetser (1860-1920), 1897 (Box 40, Folder 1782)
        - Bullard, Rev. Asa (1804-1888), 1887 (Box 40, Folder 1783)
        - Bacon-Barnes, 1860-1901 (Box 40, Folder 1784)
        - Bellows, C.A. (fragment), undated (Box 40, Folder 1785)
        - Beecher - Burlingame, 1868-1901 (Box 40, Folder 1786)
        - C.G. Hayes and Bro., 1860-1862 (Box 40, Folder 1787)
        - Case, William Cullen, undated (Box 40, Folder 1788)
        - Child, Rev. Frank Samuel (1854-1922), 1893-1899 (Box 40, Folder 1789)
        - Clarke, William Barker (1849-1905), 1859-1901, undated (Box 40, Folder 1790)
        - Congregational Clerical Union, 1902 (Box 40, Folder 1791)
        - Congregational Church of Norwich, N.Y., 1887 (Box 40, Folder 1792)
        - C.L. Ingersoll - Curtis, 1837-1899 (Box 40, Folder 1793)
        - Denman, George, 1860 (Box 41, Folder 1794)
        - Denman, Louis, [1860] (Box 41, Folder 1795)
        - Devan, Harriet, 1902 (Box 41, Folder 1796)
        - Devan, Harriet Beecher (Scoville), 1879-1899, undated, 1890-1901, undated (Box 41, Folder 1797-1799)
        - Devan, Scoville Thomas, 1902 (Box 41, Folder 1800)
        - Devan, Spencer C., 1888-1892 (Box 41, Folder 1801)
        - Daniels - Dixon, 1895-1902 (Box 41, Folder 1802)
        - Everest, C.H., 1862-1869 (Box 41, Folder 1803)
        - Ewens, E.E., 1863-1879 (Box 41, Folder 1804)
        - Eliot - Excelsior, 1860-1874 (Box 41, Folder 1805)
        - Fairfield County [Conn.] Temporary Home, 1895 (Box 41, Folder 1806)
        - First Congregational Church of Stamford, Conn., 1887 (Box 41, Folder 1807)
        - First Congregational Society of Stamford, Connecticut., 1895 (Box 41, Folder 1808)
        - Frost, S.T., 1859, undated (Box 41, Folder 1809)
        - Farrand - Fritz, 1871-1899 (Box 41, Folder 1810)
        - Gladden, Rev. Washington, 1889 (Box 41, Folder 1811)
        - Grand Army of the Republic Hobbie Post, No. 23., 1893 (Box 41, Folder 1812)
        - Gold - Grant, 1860-1899 (Box 41, Folder 1813)
        - Halliday, Rev. Samuel Byram (1812-1897), 1879, undated (Box 41, Folder 1814)
        - Hamlin - Himrod, 1860-1896 (Box 41, Folder 1815)
        - Hillis, Rev. Newell Dwight, 1902 (Box 41, Folder 1816)
        - Hitchcock, Edward, 1898 (Box 41, Folder 1817)
        - Hosford and Sons, 1870 (Box 41, Folder 1818)
        - Howard, John Raymond (1837-1926), 1860-1869 (Box 41, Folder 1819)
        - Hayes - Hubbell, 1858-1894 (Box 41, Folder 1820)
        - Inslee, Gage, 1887-1899 (Box 41, Folder 1821)
        - Johnson, C.R., 1879-1887 (Box 41, Folder 1822)
        - Johnson, Gerlinde L.D., 1879-1887 (Box 41, Folder 1823)
        - King, Horatio Collins, (1837-1918), 1874-1899 (Box 41, Folder 1824)
        - Kingsley, Lewis, 1861-1871 (Box 41, Folder 1825)
        - Jackson - Knapp, 1869-1894 (Box 41, Folder 1826)
        - Langdon - Lyon, 1856-1895 (Box 41, Folder 1827)
        - McLaw - Murrin, 1879-1900 (Box 41, Folder 1828)
        - New York Association for Improving the Condition of the Poor; and Charity Organization Society of the City of New York, 1899 (Box 41, Folder 1829)
        - Newton - Nicholas, 1863-1899 (Box 41, Folder 1830)
        - Ober, Sarah Endicott, [1899] (Box 41, Folder 1831)
        - Parker, Rev. Joseph, 1888-1897, undated (Box 41, Folder 1832)
        - Penniman, Rev. Alford Brown, 1900 (Box 41, Folder 1833)
        - Plymouth Church, Brooklyn, 1901 (Box 41, Folder 1834)
        - Pond, James Burton (1838-1903), 1899 (Box 41, Folder 1835)
        - Palmer - Putnam, 1870-1885 (Box 41, Folder 1836)
        - Raymond, Rossiter Worthington, 1887-1902 (Box 41, Folder 1837)
        - Ryder, Rev. C.J., 1899 (Box 41, Folder 1838)
        - Rexford - Rudd, 1879, 1902 (Box 41, Folder 1839)
        - Scoville, Annie Beecher, 1872-1883 October, 1884 January-1886 October, 1882-1885 Sep, 1887 June-1896 July, 1897-1901, undated, 1885 October-1886 Apr, 1886-1891 Feb, 1891 June-1892 May, 1892 October-1893 Sep, 1896 July-1898 Apr, 1898 August-1902 Apr, undated (Box 42, Folder 1840-1862)
        - Scoville, Eliza, 1860-1902, undated (Box 43, Folder 1863-1864)
        - Scoville, Harriet E.B., 1859-1861, 1866-1869, 1871-1880, 1884-1895, 1899-1901, undated (Box 43, Folder 1865-1872)
        - Scoville, Irving (?), 1882 (Box 43, Folder 1873)
        - Scoville, Jacob, 1859-1878, undated (Box 43, Folder 1874)
        - Scoville, Jacob (fragment), undated (Box 43, Folder 1875)
        - Scoville, Mrs. Jacob, undated (Box 43, Folder 1876)
        - Scoville, Louise (Armstrong), 1902 (Box 43, Folder 1877)
        - Scoville, Marian, undated (Box 43, Folder 1878)
        - Scoville, Ralph I., 1875-1883 (Box 43, Folder 1879)
        - Scoville, Ralph I. With letter from James Allyn to Ralph Scoville on verso., 1879 (Box 43, Folder 1880)
        - Scoville, Samuel [uncle?], 1871-1875 (Box 43, Folder 1881)
        - Scoville, Samuel, Jr., 1889-1893, 1899-1901, 1891-1895 (Box 43, Folder 1882-1884)
        - Scoville, Samuel, R. [nephew], 1882-1902 (Box 43, Folder 1885)
        - Scoville, William Herbert, 1891-1902, undated (Box 43, Folder 1886)
        - Stamford, Connecticut, Office of the Selectmen, 1891-1892 (Box 43, Folder 1887)
        - Stowe, Calvin Ellis and Harriet Beecher, 1859 (Box 43, Folder 1888)
        - Stowe, Harriet Elizabeth (Beecher), [1861] (Box 43, Folder 1889)
        - Strong, Augustus H., 1858-1859 (Box 43, Folder 1890)
        - St. John - Swartout, 1871-1899 (Box 43, Folder 1891)
        - Tatlock, Herbert P., 1896-1899 (Box 43, Folder 1892)
        - Trumbull, C.G., 1889-1901 (Box 43, Folder 1893)
        - Tyler, Moses Coit (1835-1900), 1861-1895 (Box 43, Folder 1894)
        - Tatlock-Tucker, 1879-1899 (Box 43, Folder 1895)
        - U.S. Christian Commission, 1865 (Box 43, Folder 1896)
        - Upton, Rev. Augustine G., 1887 (Box 43, Folder 1897)
        - Vail - Vintner, 1879-1901 (Box 44, Folder 1898)
        - Washington, Booker Taliaferro (1839?-1915), 1892 (Box 44, Folder 1899)
        - William Kempton and Co., 1862 (Box 44, Folder 1900)
        - Webster - Williams, 1879-1902 (Box 44, Folder 1901)
        - Unidentified, 1858-1899 undated (Box 44, Folder 1902)
      - From Rev. S. S.:
        - Beecher family. (Box 44, Folder 1903)
          See: Box 1, Folder 49 Box 2, Folder 89
        - Beecher, E.W.B. (Box 44, Folder 1904)
          See: Box 5, Folders 213-215
        - Blacker, R.R., 1893 (Box 44, Folder 1905)
        - Clarke, Daniel, 1869 (Box 44, Folder 1906)
        - First Congregational Church and Society of Vineland, N.J., 1901 (Box 44, Folder 1907)
        - Hartwell, J.B., 1892 (Box 44, Folder 1908)
        - Horton, 1894 (Box 44, Folder 1909)
        - Howard, John Raymond, 1860 (Box 44, Folder 1910)
        - Howard, Susan Taylor (Raymond), 1861-1895 (Box 44, Folder 1911)
        - Hurtls, 1895 (Box 44, Folder 1912)
        - Marshall, William Edgar, 1886 (Box 44, Folder 1913)
        - Plymouth Church, Brooklyn Church Work Committee, 1901 (Box 44, Folder 1914)
        - Raymond, Rossiter Worthington, 1901 (Box 44, Folder 1915)
        - Scoville Family members. (Box 44, Folder 1916)
          See: Box 18, Folder 683 Box 18, Folder 687 Box 18, Folder 705 Box 30, Folders 1320-1332
        - Scoville, A.B. (Box 44, Folder 1917)
          See: Box 30, Folders 1320-1332
        - Scoville, H.E.B. (Box 44, Folder 1918)
          See: Box 38, Folders 1705-1721
        - Scoville, Jacob, 1859-1860 (Box 44, Folder 1919)
        - Scoville, Mrs. Jacob, [1860] (Box 44, Folder 1920)
        - Scoville, [Ralph I.], [1860] (Box 44, Folder 1921)
        - His children, 1882-1897 (Box 44, Folder 1922)
        - Thompson, James G., [1869] (Box 44, Folder 1923)
        - Revs. Vail, Downey and Rhodes, 1893 (Box 44, Folder 1924)
        - Unidentified, 1872-1884 (Box 44, Folder 1925)
    - Stowe, Harriet E. (Beecher)
      - To H.E.B.S.:
        - Beecher, Eunice White (Bullard), [183- - 1846] (Box 44, Folder 1926)
        - Parker, Rev. Joel, 1852 (Box 44, Folder 1927)
        - Parker, Rev. Joel. (Box 44, Folder 1928)
          See: Box 13, Folder 522 Box 44, Folder 1942 Box 1, Folder 58 Box 46, Folder 2064
        - Warner, Charles Dudley, 1875 (Box 44, Folder 1929)
      - From H. E. B. S.:
        - Beecher Family. (Box 44, Folder 1930)
          See: Box 1, Folders 19 Box 1, Folders 53 Box 2, Folder 106
        - Beecher, Eunice W. B. (Box 44, Folder 1931)
          See: Box 5, Folders 223-224
        - Beecher, Henry Ward. (Box 44, Folder 1932)
          See: Box 15, Folders 595-600
        - [Bullard?], Lizzie [copy enclosed note from H. W. B.], [1861] (Box 44, Folder 1933)
        - Gunn, Frederick William, 1862-1864 (Box 44, Folder 1934)
        - Edward, John Raymond, [1870's] (Box 44, Folder 1935)
        - Howard, Susan Taylor (Raymond), [1858?] (Box 44, Folder 1936)
        - Kinney, undated (Box 44, Folder 1937)
        - Raymond, Rossiter Worthington, 1875 (Box 44, Folder 1938)
        - Stowe, Harriet Elisabeth (Beecher). (Box 44, Folder 1939)
          See: Box 1, Folder 22
        - Scoville, H. E. B. (Box 44, Folder 1940)
          See: Box 39, Folder 1739
    - Stowe Family
      - Stowe, A. M.
        - Herrit, Mrs., 1863, 1867 (Box 44, Folder 1941)
      - Stowe, Calvin Ellis
        - To C.E.S.:
          - Parker, Rev. Joel, 1852 (Box 44, Folder 1942)
          - Stowe, Harriet Elisabeth (Beecher), 1836 (Box 44, Folder 1943)
        - From C.E.S.:
          - Gunn, Frederick William, 1864 (Box 44, Folder 1944)
  - Correspondence of Others
    - Beecher, Lyman
      - Birney, James G. to Lewis Tappan [photostate], 1837 (Box 45, Folder 1945)
      - U.S.- Smithsonian Institution to Plymouth Church, re: Lyman Beecher trust, 1926 (Box 45, Folder 1946)
    - Beecher, Henry Ward
      - Bazley, Thomas to Robert Trimble, 1863 (Box 45, Folder 1947)
      - Bonner, Robert (1824-1899) (Box 45, Folder 1948)
      - Bonner, Robert to The New York Express, undated (Box 45, Folder 1949)
      - Cavan, David to Samuel Cavan, 1863 (Box 45, Folder 1950)
      - Curtis, George William to Burrill, 1863 (Box 45, Folder 1951)
      - Fern, Fanny (pseud) [Parton, Sara Payson (Willis)] to Robert Bonner, undated (Box 45, Folder 1952)
      - Gaslin, C.C. to Christian Union, 1883 (Box 45, Folder 1953)
      - Gottsburger (?), Williams to James Cephas Derby, 1884 (Box 45, Folder 1954)
      - H. & A. Stursberg, N.Y. to H. & A. Stursberg, Berlin, 1863 (Box 45, Folder 1955)
      - Halliday, Rev. Samuel Byram to [H. W.?] Cleaveland, 1875 (Box 45, Folder 1956)
      - Howard, John Raymond to Rev. Crammond Kennedy, 1870 (Box 45, Folder 1957)
      - Kennedy, Rev. Crammond to John Howard Raymond, 1870 (Box 45, Folder 1958)
      - Ketchum, Edgar to M. E. Strieby, 1877 (Box 45, Folder 1959)
      - Leighton, Andrew to [C. C.?] Duncan, 1863 (Box 45, Folder 1960)
      - Livingston, Mrs. B.J. to Editor, Peoples Monthly, 1875 (Box 45, Folder 1961)
      - Montague, George to Sarah P. Ferry, 1887 (Box 45, Folder 1962)
      - Morgan, William to C. P. Melly, 1863 (Box 45, Folder 1963)
      - Ovington, Mary White to George Foster Peabody, 1915 (Box 45, Folder 1964)
      - Parton, I. to Robert Bonner, 1964 (Box 45, Folder 1965)
      - Peabody, George Foster to Mary White Ovington, 1915 (Box 45, Folder 1966)
      - Pelletier, Claude to Louis Blanc, 1863 (Box 45, Folder 1967)
      - Pelletier, Claude to Victor Hugo, 1863 (Box 45, Folder 1968)
      - Rathbone, Lewis to Henry C. Bowen, [1857?] (Box 45, Folder 1969)
      - Robinson, C. to Eli Thayer, 1856 (Box 45, Folder 1970)
      - Saeljer [?], Alexander and Lawrence B. Valk to Plymouth Church Trustees, [1859] (Box 45, Folder 1971)
      - Stoddard, A.L. to P. Sinclair enclosing letter from Edward Alexander, 1863 (Box 45, Folder 1972)
      - Stone, Sidney M. to Plymouth Church Trustees, 1859 (Box 45, Folder 1973)
      - Tomkins, Frederick to Geheimrath Millermaier, 1863 (Box 45, Folder 1974)
      - Zundel, John to A.S. Barnes, 1879 (Box 45, Folder 1975)
      - Unidentified Fragment re: H.W.B.'s role in Cleveland Campaign, 1884 (Box 45, Folder 1976)
      - Unidentified to Taft, re: William Ives Budington's Church, 1874 (Box 45, Folder 1977)
    - The Tilton Scandal
      - Allon, Rev. Henry to Rev. T. J. Conant, 1875 (Box 45, Folder 1978)
      - Bacon, Rev. Leonard to Rev. James B. Walker enclosing copy of a walker's letter in the Christian Cynosure (Box 45, Folder 1979)
      - Barrows, Rev. John Henry to Rev. William Brunet Wright, 1875 (Box 45, Folder 1980)
      - Benedict, Charles to Henry M. Cleveland, 1876 (Box 45, Folder 1981)
      - Billings, Charles Ethan to Rev. Joshua Wyman Wellman, 1876 (Box 45, Folder 1982)
      - Blake, Rev. Silas Leroy to Rev. Joshua Wyman Wellman, [1876] (Box 45, Folder 1983)
      - Bouton, N. (fragment) Letter on Brooklyn Council (Box 45, Folder 1984)
      - Brooklyn Council of 1876 Document (Box 45, Folder 1985)
      - Bulkley, C.H.A to Oliver Johnson, 1875 (Box 45, Folder 1986)
      - Christensen, C.T. to John Tasker Howard, 1874 (Box 45, Folder 1987)
      - Church of the Pilgrims and Clintin Avenue Church to Plymouth Church, 1873 (Box 45, Folder 1988)
      - Crosby, Judah to Rev. Joshua Wyman Wellman, 1876 (Box 45, Folder 1989)
      - Dwight, Timothy to Rev. Joshua Wyman Wellman, 1876-1877 (Box 45, Folder 1990)
      - Everest, Charles Hall to Undentified, 1875 (Box 45, Folder 1991)
      - Greene, Rev. Richard Gleason to Rev. Joshua Wyman Wellman, 1876 (Box 45, Folder 1992)
      - Gresham, R.H. to Field., 1874 (Box 45, Folder 1992a)
        See: Box 98
      - Hayward, Silvanus to Rev. Joshua Wyman Wellman, 1876 (Box 45, Folder 1993)
      - Helmer, C.C. to [William Buell?] Sprague, 1874 (Box 45, Folder 1994)
      - Holbrook, Rev. John C. to Rev. Lyman Abbott, 1877 (Box 45, Folder 1995)
      - Howard, John Raymond, Memorandum of a conversation with Rev. Richard Salter Storrs, Jr., 1873 (Box 45, Folder 1996)
      - Hubbard, R.C. to Egbert Coffin Smyth [copy], 1876 (Box 45, Folder 1997)
      - Hutchinson, J.B. to Rev. Joshua Wyman Wellman, 1876 (Box 45, Folder 1998)
      - Stone, T.A. to Plymouth Church, Brooklyn, 1874 (Box 45, Folder 1999)
      - Judkins, T.J. to Henry M. Cleveland, 1876 (Box 45, Folder 2000)
      - King, Horatio Collins to [David Otis Mears], 1876 (Box 45, Folder 2001)
      - Lloyd, W.A. to Robert Raikes Raymond, 1875 (Box 45, Folder 2002)
      - Mears, Rev. David Otis to Rev. [Henry Martin] Storrs, 1876 (Box 45, Folder 2003)
      - Merrill, Rev. James Griswold to Rev. Joshua Wyman Wellman, 1876 (Box 45, Folder 2004)
      - Oshorne, Rev. Cyrus Pearl to Rev. Joshua Wyman Wellman, 1876 (Box 45, Folder 2005)
      - Palmer, Ray to [Mark] Hopkins, 1876 (Box 45, Folder 2006)
      - Phelps, Aurora H.C. to William Maxwell Evarts, [c. 1875] (Box 45, Folder 2007)
      - Phelps, Austin to Rev. Joshua Wyman Wellman, 1876 (Box 45, Folder 2008)
      - Plymouth Church, Brooklyn, draft of a letter missive to an unidentified church, [1876] (Box 45, Folder 2009)
      - Plymouth Church Trustees to Moses Sperry Beach, 1875 (Box 45, Folder 2010)
      - Plymouth Church, Framingham, Mass. to Plymouth Church, Brooklyn, 1876 (Box 45, Folder 2011)
      - Poor, T.P. to M. P. Kennard, undated (Box 45, Folder 2012)
      - Porter, Rev. Noah to [Rev. Samuel Byram Halliday], 1875 (Box 45, Folder 2013)
      - Porter, Rev. Noah to Rev. [Joshua Wyman] Wellman, 1876 (Box 45, Folder 2014)
      - Shaw, D.R. to H. W. Sage, 1874 (Box 45, Folder 2015)
      - Spalding. Rev. George Burley to Rev. Joshua Wyman Wellman, 1876 (Box 45, Folder 2016)
      - Staats (?), Henry to Rev. J. W. Wellman, 1876 (Box 45, Folder 2017)
      - Storrs, Rev. Henry Martyn to Rev, Joshua Wyman Wellman, 1876 (Box 45, Folder 2018)
      - Strong, Edward to Mark Hopkins, 1876 (Box 45, Folder 2019)
      - Thayer, Alexander Wheelock to Rev. T. J. Conant, 1875 (Box 45, Folder 2020)
      - Tilton, Elizabeth fragments on H.W.B.'s relationship to her husband, undated (Box 45, Folder 2021)
      - Wellman, A.E. to Rev. Joshua Wyman Wellman, 1876 (Box 45, Folder 2022)
      - Wolcott, Samuel to Rev. Henry Martyn Dexter, 1873 (Box 45, Folder 2023)
      - Unsigned statement of Congregational Polity, 1873 (Box 45, Folder 2024)
    - Seventieth Birthday Celebration
      - Seventieth Birthday Celebration, 1883 (Box 45, Folder 2025)
      - Seventieth Birthday Letters, 1883 (Box 45, Folder 2026)
    - Death of Henry Ward Beecher
      - Bok, Edward W. Circular on the H.W.S. Memorial addressed to [Moses Sperry Beach] (Box 45, Folder 2027)
      - Hall, Rev. Charles H. to James Burton Pond, 1887 September 26 (Box 45, Folder 2028)
      - Pond, James Burton to Emily Mervine Drury, 1887 (Box 45, Folder 2029)
      - Sherman, William Tecumseh to James Burton Pond [copy], 1887 (Box 45, Folder 2030)
      - Death of H.W.B. (Box 45, Folder 2031)
        See: Box 77, Folder 29
    - Scoville, Annie Beecher
      - Bates, Katharine Lee, testimonial for Annie Beecher Scoville's lectures, 1904 July 22 (Box 46, Folder 2032)
      - Bates, Katharine Lee to Chase, undated (Box 46, Folder 2033)
      - Burt, Kate W. to Miss Kendrick, undated (Box 46, Folder 2034)
      - Claflin, Mary B. to Clark (Box 46, Folder 2035)
      - Farley, Rosalie to Mrs. Conwell, 1894 (Box 46, Folder 2036)
      - Gilfillan, J.A. to Various, 1903 (Box 46, Folder 2037)
      - Guthrie, Sheila to William Jones, 1898 (Box 46, Folder 2038)
      - Hampton Normal and Agricultural Institute to W. H. Cummings, 1897 (Box 46, Folder 2039)
      - Hurlbutt, Lewis R. Certificate of Health for Annie Scoville, 1885 (Box 46, Folder 2040)
      - Jones, William to Katharine Lee Bates, 1895 (Box 46, Folder 2041)
      - Kinkead, George B. to Mrs. Parkinson, 1942 (Box 46, Folder 2042)
      - King, Henry C. to Rev. Alfred G. Walton, 1921 (Box 46, Folder 2043)
      - Lewis, Harriet H. to Mrs. Albert Howe, 1893 (Box 46, Folder 2044)
      - Moores, Charles W. to Unidentified, undated (Box 46, Folder 2045)
      - Phillips, Alfred N. to Connecticut State Park and Forest Commission, 1924 (Box 46, Folder 2046)
      - Phillips, Alfred N. Jr. to William H. Hyland, 1924 (Box 46, Folder 2047)
      - Repplier, Agnes to Florence Holbrook, 1922 (Box 46, Folder 2048)
      - Silber, Edith A. to Miss Parmley, undated (Box 46, Folder 2049)
      - Turnbull, Grace P. to Various, 1915, undated (Box 46, Folder 2050)
      - Ward, Kate M. to Parmley, 1921 (Box 46, Folder 2051)
      - Women's City Club of Boston to Miss Curtis, 1914 (Box 46, Folder 2052)
      - Woolley, Mary E., Testimonial for Annie Beecher Scoville's lectures, 1904 July 26 (Box 46, Folder 2053)
    - Scoville, Harriet E. B.
      - Unidentified to [Bullard?], Lizzie, 1897 (Box 46, Folder 2054)
    - Scoville, Rev. Samuel
      - Beard, Rev. Augustus F. to Rev. Newell Dwight Hillis, 1902 (Box 46, Folder 2055)
      - Denman [George] to Brodie, undated (Box 46, Folder 2056)
      - [Denman, George] to Lewis [Denman], undated (Box 46, Folder 2057)
      - Low, Samson to Thomas Constable, 1860 (Box 46, Folder 2058)
      - N. Y. S. Volunteers 159th Regiment Veteran Association to Rev. Newell Dwight Hillis, 1902 (Box 46, Folder 2059)
      - Ryder, C. J. Testimonial for Scoville's Lecture on H. B. S. and H. W. B., 1899 (Box 46, Folder 2060)
      - U.S. Army Quartermaster's Office to Captain of U.S. Transport Arago (Box 46, Folder 2061)
    - Stowe, Harriet E. Beecher
      - Cleveland, Charles D. to Lewis Tappan, [1852] (Box 46, Folder 2062)
      - Rood, A. to Lewis Tappan, 1852 (Box 46, Folder 2063)
      - Letters to editors of the Independent re: Joel Parker Uncle Tom's Cabin controversy, 1852 (Box 46, Folder 2064)
    - Stowe, Frederick William
      - Rosteri, L. to Alessandro Maccaresi, letter of introduction for Frederick William Stowe and Samuel Scoville, 1859 (Box 46, Folder 2065)
    - Correspondence of Others: General
      - Boilvin, N. to Col, Bayer, 1818 July 18 (Box 46, Folder 2066)
      - Letter of Introduction from J.C. Cook for Mr. Blake, who was bringing a young mulatto girl north to B.M. Campbell, 1859 (Box 46, Folder 2067)
      - Terry, Dame Ellen to Unidentified correspondent (fragment) (Box 46, Folder 2068)
      - Terry, S.F. to [A grandson of H.W.B.?] (Box 46, Folder 2069)
      - Miscellaneous, 1826-1880, undated, 1890-1915 (Box 46, Folder 2070-2071)
- Writings, Speeches, and Research Materials, 1839-1945; Series II; 9' 7" (23 boxes)
  This series is arranged alphabetically by the name of the family member, followed by a small group of non-family materials, "Writings of Others." The two largest groups, "Henry Ward Beecher" and "Annie Beecher Scoville", are further divided according to the type of material and, with the exception of sermons, are arranged either chronologically or alphabetically by title and subject.